averydennison.com 2017-11-25

# Legal and Privacy Notices | Avery Dennison

###   
**SITE ACCESS**

By accessing this web site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of use appearing below, such use being non-commercial in nature and conditional on your acceptance.

### **DISCLAIMER**

Nothing on any Avery Dennison web site shall be construed as conferring any license or right under any of Avery Dennison's or any third party rights whether by estoppel, implication or otherwise.

Although the information is provided on this server to anyone, we retain the copyright on all text and graphic images. This means you may not distribute the text or graphics to others without the express written permission of Avery Dennison; modify or re-use the text or graphics to others without the express written permission of Avery Dennison; modify or re-use the text or graphics on this system. You may print copies of the information for your own personal use; store the files on your own computer for your personal use only; and reference hypertext documents on this server from your own documents.

Avery Dennison also reserves all other rights, including the right to make changes or corrections at any time without notice. You are prohibited from posting or transmitting any unlawful, threatening, libelous, defamatory, obscene, scandalous, inflammatory, pornographic, objectionable or profane material or any materials that could constitute or encourage conduct that would be considered a criminal offense, give rise to civil liability or otherwise violate any law. Avery Dennison will fully cooperate with law enforcement authorities or court order requesting or directing Avery Dennison to disclose the identity of or help identify or locate anyone posting any such information or materials. Avery Dennison makes no commitment to update the information provided herein.

The information, text, graphics and links provided herein are provided by Avery Dennison or third-party service providers as a convenience to its customers. This web site contains links to other sites. The links are meant for the user's convenience only. Avery Dennison has no control over, and is not responsible for, content found on external sites that do not belong to Avery Dennison Corporation ("third-party sites"). Links to third party sites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement or approval of these sites or the content on these sites. This web site may contain content not generated by Avery Dennison. Avery Dennison is not responsible for any third-party content.

The name of Avery Dennison Corporation or the Avery Dennison logo may not be used in advertising or publicity pertaining to distribution of the information on or linked to this web site or any other server or "hot-linked" sites without specific, written prior permission. Avery Dennison and its third-party service providers make no representation or warranties about the accuracy, currency, completeness or suitability of the information provided herein and will not be held liable for any use of this information for any purpose. It is provided "as is" without express or implied warranty.

The material provided on this site is protected by law, including, but not limited to, United States Copyright Law and international treaties. This site is controlled and operated by Avery Dennison from its offices within the State of California, United States of America. Avery Dennison makes no representation that materials in the site are appropriate or available for use in other locations. Those who choose to access this site from other locations do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, if and to the extent applicable.

Please do not use the information in this site for any formal analysis or estimates.

AVERY DENNISON DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THE INFORMATION PROVIDED ON THE WEB SITE OR OTHER SITES "HOT LINKED" TO THIS SITE, INCLUDING ALL EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. IN NO EVENT SHALL AVERY DENNISON BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA, SALES, OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN A CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING OUT OF ACCESS TO, USE OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE, INABILITY TO USE, ACCURACY OR SUITABILITY OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS INFORMATION.

ANY CLAIM RELATED TO THE INFORMATION ON THIS WEB SITE SHALL BE GOVERNED BY THE LAWS OF DELAWARE.

### **PRIVACY STATEMENT**

We at Avery Dennison value our customers and take great pride in assuring that their privacy is maintained. It is important that we maintain an environment where our customers feel comfortable that the information they provide us with will not be misused. We believe every customer should be able to conduct business with us without having their personal information used for unrelated purposes. This document provides guidelines that Avery Dennison uses to ensure proper handling of all customer information.

**_PRIVACY & COOKIES POLICY  
_**Avery Dennison protects its customers' right to privacy. The following guidelines outline the handling of all customer information passed through this Web site and other Avery Dennison operated websites.

**_AVERY DENNISON CUSTOMER PRIVACY POLICY GUIDELINES_**

In general, when you visit our Web sites and access information, you remain anonymous. We collect personal information from visitors to our sites on a voluntary basis only and explain how this information will be used at the time it is requested.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

We may collect the following information:

  * name, title, company, address, phone number
  * contact information including email address
  * other information that you enter on forms on this website

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER?**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We use the personal information we collect to respond to online queries, supply requested information on Avery Dennison products, process and ship orders, fulfill online marketing offers, establish approved links and for internal market analysis.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided. 
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise this website according to your interests.
  * We may use the information for the specific purpose stated on forms on this website.

We will obtain your prior permission before we contact you, if this is legally required.

**_DO WE SELL PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES?_  
**We do not sell or rent personal information to third parties.

Our Web servers collect the domain names of visitors to our sites. We also use third party services such as Google Analytics to collect information about visitors to our websites. This information is aggregated to determine number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed, etc. We use this information to measure site usage, as well as to improve the content and value of our site.

[[click here]](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) More information about the way Google processes your information. If you wish to disable Google Analytics on your browser, please follow [[](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)these steps]

**_SECURITY_  
**We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**_LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES_  
**This site may contain links to other third party sites. We take steps to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy. However, we are not responsible for the privacy standards and practices of third parties. We encourage you to read and understand the privacy policy of every website you visit.

Avery Dennison strives to keep online visitor information secure against unauthorized access and use. This information is protected by Company security measures, which are reviewed periodically.

**_COOKIES_**

Some of our Web pages may contain "cookies," which send and store data on your Web browser. This allows our server(s) to recognize you and better serve you when you visit our Web sites in the future. Most Web browsers can be configured to not accept cookies, or to notify you if a cookie is sent to you.

**_WEBSITE COOKIES  
_**You can visit our website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information. If you give us any personal information about yourself or others we promise to treat it securely, fairly and lawfully. We are committed to protecting your privacy. When we ask you for personal information it will only be in response to you actively using our online products or communication services (e.g. e-mail).

**_COOKIES – WHAT ARE THEY?  
_**Cookies are small text files stored on your computer, tablet or phone when you visit a website. They are widely used in order to make websites work more effectively. Some cookies are deleted when you close down your browser (session cookies). Others remain on your device until they expire or you delete them from your cache (persistent cookies or tracking code) and enable us to remember things about you as a returning visitor.

For more information about cookies, visit  **www.allaboutcookies.org**   

**_How do we use cookies?  
_**We use cookies to:  
• Provide a secure online environment where required.  
• Enhance user experience by remembering a users login details.  
• Track website performance in order to improve the website’s usability and give you a better online experience and track.

**_Giving you a better online experience and tracking website performance  
_**We use the following type of cookies to understand how visitors use our online services and look for ways to improve them. For example, a cookie might tell us that lots of people give up on a certain stage in the process – we can then use this information to make that step a lot easier to use for all our customers.

Cookie Type

| 

Purpose  
  
---|---  
  
Session cookie

| 

Expires at the end of your session:

Used to track progress through the site and length of visit.

Stores your username and password associated with certain areas of the site, plus information about your account and keeps you logged in for the duration of your visit.  
  
 Tracking code

| 

Does not contain personal information

Keeps track of where a visit came from, what search engine was used, what link was clicked on, what keyword was used, and where in the world visitor was when accessing the website.

Tracks amount of visits, and the time of the first, the previous, and the current visit.

Remembers (if selected) user name and password for the Avery Dennison website you are visiting.

Remembers if you have completed a software registration form before.  

You can delete cookies relating to our websites, but we will not remember things about you, including your cookie preferences, and you will be treated as a first-time visitor the next time you visit a website.

**_ARE YOU HAPPY FOR US TO USE COOKIES?  
_**Some features are designed to give you a better online experience and only work if we use cookies. If you continue to use this website, you consent to use of all cookies on our website. You can change your mind at any time, but please note that certain ‘essential’ cookies allow our customers to flow freely through some of our Office and Consumer Products websites, and design and save their products. Also we only use cookies for measuring website performance and visit regularity. Cookies on our Office and Consumer Products websites are used to remember any account details when visiting that Avery Dennison website, removing your cookies will mean you have to log in to the application and register each time you use it.

**_OPT-OUT PROCESS_**

 _  
_

We believe our customers should have the right to decline disclosure of personal information that is collected on our databases. The records for those individuals who request that their personal information not be used for future mailings will be marked in our database so that their names will be excluded from any contact in the future.

Customers can request removal of their name and customer information by the following methods:

  * For Office and Consumer Products customers by calling the respective Avery Dennison Customer Service Centre, Monday to Friday between the hours of 10am - 4pm.
  * For our Materials and RBIS customers by contacting the local Marketing Communications contacts, details of which are to be found in the latest mailing you have received.

**_Avery Dennison Customer Information Sources_**

_Avery Dennison's customer information is collected when customers:_

  * Call Avery Dennison Customer Service Center (CSC). When customers call the CSC, we might ask for their names, address, phone number, and other customer profile information that helps us better serve their needs in the future. This information helps facilitate communication with our customers by allowing us to quickly and efficiently identify the customer.
  * Respond to various marketing campaigns (i.e., advertisements, business reply cards, offers, etc.). This customer information collected is completely voluntary. In most cases, customers are given a choice to have their names removed by checking the appropriate box on the questionnaire.

**_Email Processes_**

We would only use online email communication with customers who have given us permission to do so. When used, we will provide our customers with a mechanism through which they can request that Avery Dennison omit their email addresses from lists or databases. We will always provide our customers with an email address, postal address, and telephone number at which we can be contacted.

**WHAT IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO RECEIVE ANY INFORMATION?  
**  
_GENERAL  
_If you would rather not receive any information about the activities, products and services of Avery Dennison , you can indicate this by sending a letter to this effect and enclosing a copy of your proof of identity to Avery Dennison at the e-mail address below.

_E-MAIL SERVICES  
_Providing electronic services is important to Avery Dennison, particularly because these e-services offer customers, prospective customers and website visitors quick and convenient access to information. When you subscribe to receiving communications by e-mail, - where such service is offered - you are giving Avery Dennison permission to use your e-mail address for that specific purpose.

**QUESTIONS  
**If you have any questions requests with regard to this policy, please contact us at:

Avery Dennison Corp  
Attn: Corporate Communications  
Email: [dataprivacy@averydennison.com](mailto:dataprivacy@averydennison.com)

**CHANGES    
**Avery Dennison may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. This policy is effective from 14th January 2013.

### **TRADEMARK NOTICE**

Avery, Avery Dennison, Design "A" logo and all other Avery Dennison brands, product names and codes are trademarks of Avery Dennison Corporation.  All other brands and product names are trademarks of their respective owners. Personal and company names and other information on samples depicted are fictitious.  Any resemblance to actual names and addresses is purely coincidental.
